A Doramissic Crisis
Bro, are you ready?
Sure. But, I have not told Nobita yet.
Bad bro!
Ma' Dad is pretty good at dancin'...
so I should choregraphy for the party
I had enough!
Hi, you guys!
Dekisugi-san!
What? You went to see the dinosaur exhibit?
I bet it was fantastic!
Yeah, it was truly fascinating.
I can't believe such a huge creature once roamed around this planet...
The Ultrasaurus which was even bigger than Brachiosaurus...
It is hard to even imagine how huge it must have been!
Exactly!
We have not seen the real one, after all.
It's physical strength is leagues beyond your imagination!
You saw a real dinosaur?
Once we went with Doraemon.
Tyrannosaurus was truly tyrannic.
Right, Nobita?
I have grown tired of seeing them.
Hey, Giant, let's play a dinosaur game at my home.
Sure thing, ma' true buddy...
It's even better than a real one!
Really?
See you!
They're too much!
Right!
Seeing one in flesh ain't such a big deal!
Dekisugi-san is much knowledgeable about dinosaurs than them, I bet.
You flatter me.
I wanted to see Ultrasaurus raising their young ones.
Dekisugi-kun, I'll ask Doraemon to take us to the period of Ultrasaurus.
I too want to see the dinosaurs, all of a sudden...
Really?
Really? I am so happy
Seeing the real Ultrasaurus is like a dream.
I wanna go too!
Of course, you can!
Then let's ask Doraemon!
It's time!
Bro, I'll take care of everything here.
Watch over Nobita-kun!
Now, hurry...
Have you forgot anything?
The hospital card.
Bad bro!
Where did I put it?
The doc won't see you if you don't bring your card.
I can't find it.
Doraemon!
Dorami-chan!
Nobita-san, welcome home.
Hiya, Dorami-chan!
Hi, Shizuka-chan and Dekisugi-san!
Where is Doraemon?
I found it!
I left it in the pocket!
Now I will go.
Oh, Nobita-kun!
Where are you going?
Regular Helath Check-up?
I will come back as soon as possible.
Dorami will watch over you till then.
I'm going!
Dorami-chan, I have a favor to ask of you.
Go ahead! And tell me what is it?
Let's go!
Pretty please?
Please?
Sure thing!
I shall take you all to the Jurassic period in my bro's place.
Thank you, Dorami-chan!
Dekisugi-san, which period you'd like to go to?
14 million years ago at the climax of the Jurassic period.
Why?
Because the race of Ultrasaurus flourished then.
At Colorado river, in the present America, they discovered the fossils of Ultrasaurus.
You seem quite knowledgeable.
You flatter me, I just read it in the books.
Got ya!
We're ready to go!
14 million years ago.
Jurassic period, time travel, go!
Wonderful, there are cedar and straw trees all over!
It's just as described in the Encyclopedia, but the real deal is so huge.
Shall we set foot at land?
Colorado forest looks so beautiful!
We descend!
What's wrong?
There was a response in the radar!
But I see nothing!
This is the metal detector radar.
It's impossible to get metal reactions at this period.
Must be you imagining things!
Really?
It's time we go outside.
Be careful!
Yes'm!
There is an important thing I need to tell you before we get off.
Don't hurt the living beings and the flora.
Don't change the past.
Dora-chan told us before already.
Can we take a picture?
Sure thing!
Let's go!
It is warm, just as I expected!
So this climate caused the trees to grow so big?
How fresh the air is!
Indeed!
Does it hurt, Nobita-san?
Dekisugi-san, come here!
I hope we get to see Ultrasaurus.
It's Triceratops.
So fun, let's get a closer view!
Are you all right?
Triceratops is ok...
But I prefer a bigger dinosaur!
I wonder if there is?!
Woah, so big!
Dekisugi-kun, I have found a bigger one!
Take a pic of me with this giant baby!
That's the carnivorous Aursaurus.
What now?
Do something!
Oh, yes!
Let me go!
How dangerous!
Nobita-san!
We're pretty far away, We should be safe now.
Urusaurus is so willful.
Right, he must have been hungry.
Or did Nobita-san appeared tasty to it?
But I'd say Dorami would look more delicious.
What do you mean?
Do you want to say I am fat?
Not really
I want to see Ultrasaurus.
Where?
Then we set out.
The sun has set.
Let's look for it tomorrow.
Let's camp somewhere safe for now!
Portable Camping Capsule!
Quick, go in!
There are 4 rooms, you are free to choose the one that you like.
Doremi's gadget is so smart.
Shizuka-chan, I have a shower room just for you.
I am so happy
Gourmet Sheet!
Sit here.
Speak your orders and it will appear.
Because I am hungry.
I order pork in big bowl
Oh, too big a bowl
Shizuka-chan, go ahead.
I order Spaghetti meat sauce and Corn Soup!
It looks delicious!
I order pancake and milk tea!
Dekisugi-san, go on.
I order beefsteak.
Let's dig in!
How am I supposed to eat this?
The sky is so beautiful!
Jurassic sky looks so mysterious!
i hope we can see the Ultrasaurus tomorrow.
We should get up early.
I'll sleep!
A lot of things happened today.
And the dinosaurs are sleeping now.
What's that red light?
That noise?
Dorami-chan!
Dorami-chan, look!
A red light glimmered in that direction!
and I heard the dinosaurs screaming...
But I don't see anything.
You are still half-asleep.
You must have mistook a shooting star with this.
But I saw it!
Tomorrow, we should get up early.
Good night!
I did see it!
Morning, Shizuka-chan!
Morning, Dorami-chan!
Morning!
I had a deep and relaxing sleep!
Good morning, you guys!
Mornin'.
Fresh air!
What? You didn't sleep?
I was excited of hoping to see Ultrasaurus, that I couldn't get a sound sleep.
I can feel you.
I wonder where's Ultrasaurus!
The fossil was found at the lake bed of Colorado lake.
So we should head there!
So let's go!
Then we set out after dinner!
OK!
You two finished so quick?
Dorami-chan, let's fly with the bamboo 'copter.
But I forget to take the backup battery.
So let's try our best not to use it.
Anything here?
It's Hornetasaurus!
Let's hide!
Momotaro's Millet Dumplings!
These dinosaur run very fast.
Let's ride 'em and look for Ultrasaurus!
Wow, good idea!
I have ride it before, so I can ride it well.
Let's hop on 'em!
Everyone, ready?
Not yet!
I can not ride well!
Forward, hold the neck.
Mr. Dinosaur, take us to the lake side.
Nobita-san!, are you all right? Go for it!
I am alright, somehow!
Nobita-san!
Stop!
Nobita-san, hang in there!
There!
Nobita-san, let go!
Mr. Dinosaur, please calm down.
We have got this!
Thank goodness!
Look, there!
It's the lake.
There will be Ultrasaurus.
Let's go and see!
Look!
The real Ultrasaurus!
The biggest creature in the 3 billion years history of this planet.
So huge!
Tell me it's not a dream.
We are looking at the real Ultrasaurus.
Yup.
The little baby.
So huge parents with so tiny babies.
So cute!
So Ultrasaurus breed the kids in group.
Let's approach closer.
Sure, but make sure not to scare them.
So lovely!
Dorami-chan, lend me the bamboo 'copter.
Me too.
Sure!
Here you go!
So big!
Wow, I can feel them!
I feel the Ultrasaurus 30 feet!
I am so moved!
Sorry for interrupting your dinner!
Shizuka-chan, Dorami-chan, it's so huge!
It's charm is so wonderful!
Who could've done such a terrible thing?
A Nurse robot and some runts of the 20 century!
Who are you?
Why did you do such terrible thing?
It's my job!
Sell the dinosaurs.
Then you are the dinosaur hunter.
Oh, that red light shot the dinosaurs yesterday!
It's parent is taking a quick nap inside my time machine!
Hands up and go backwards!
I can sell both of them at high price.
No, you won't!
Then I'll kill you first.
Dorami-chan!
Nothing funny!
Don't take anything funny out of your 4-D pocket.
I am serious!
Hands up, say your prayers!
It was unlucky for you to play in this dangerous place!
It's not dangerous.
The Dinosaurs lived here by themselves in peace.
Those who disturbs this peace are the ones who're really dangerous!
Exactly!
What did you say?
Shizuka-chan, wake up!
Dekisugi-kun!
You go ahead!
Stop Watch!
I made it just in time!
Both of them are really scared.
Momotaro's Rice Dumplings!
Stop!
Go back to the forest.
Doraemon!
Dora-chan!
I wonder if they're ok...?
Bro!
Bro, how did you find us here?
My health checkup was finished, earlier than expected.
And Dorami's time machine was absent.
So I came following your trail.
I saved you guys at the time of "A Doramissic Crisis".
Sorry, I was careless.
Dorami-chan, are you all right?
Uh-huh.
Ouch, ouch...
Damn you dinosaur! I'll catch you later.
You ain't gettin' away!
Arrest Set!
Just give up.
Bro, Ultrasaurus's mum is in real danger.
Can you cure her?
Okay, I'll give it a try.
Take 2 pills at once, remember to drink water.
Okay, this should cure her.
Great.
Great...
Come on, guys.
We should go back soon.
Excuse me, what will happen to me?
Take me with you?
What should we do, Bro?
I've contacted the Time Police.
That's great, Doraemon!
Sure.
Doraemon, Dorami-chan!
Thank you for your taking me here.
Though unpleasant stuff happened...
It was so much fun!
I'm scared!
Please help!!!
Mr. Time Police!